[Music]
hey little guys my name is a Jenner this
mmm so good I mean latte art could use a
bit of work but really hits the spot
welcome back to my safe loss loss series
kind of this is kind of a C++ related
video but it's also a very kind of
general video and it's very very opinion
based and really we're just maybe
talking about why I personally don't
using namespace STD now this is a
question that I get asked I want to say
almost daily like people ask me that I
literally as I scroll through my
comments for the day someone on some
video always asks hey you know you
couldn't just using namespace STD and
then you're gonna have to type in a city
every time yes I do know that I do know
that but I'm not doing it on purpose and
this video is going to be talking about
why I don't do it and why you probably
shouldn't do it or maybe you should do
it it's kind of an opinion definitely
leave your thoughts in the comments
below at the end of this video but let's
get right on into this and actually
first of all talk about what using
namespace STD actually does in fact what
a using namespace is okay so if we just
open up the code that was in the
previous episode of the C++ series you
can see that I there are a lot of
instances here where I use things from
the standard library will that be
something like STD vector
CDC out here STD CN dot yeah STD
function there's a bunch of things that
I'm using from the standard library now
notice that every time I use something
from the standard library like this
fondest function I need to actually type
xtd colon colon out the front before I
actually type that function however if I
just add onto the top of this file as an
example using namespace STD just like
that then I don't actually have to do
that I can just go through all of this
and remove all the STDs in fact I'm just
going to do a fine replace as - colon
colon with nothing in this document and
there you go you can see that I can just
write my code like that and if I compile
it it will work and so immediately when
people see this they're like ah but
yeah the code looks so much cleaner I'm
gonna use this everywhere and I mean you
don't have to use this up here you can
actually just declare it locally inside
a function so like in this main function
I can just declare it here which means
it just applies to this scope and you
really can do it in any scope and then I
would still have to use sta like that
over here so you can confine it to
different skirts and I mean yeah using
namespace can be incredibly useful if
you're dealing with really long
namespaces or you've got your own
namespaces that you've declared for your
own files that are in like your own
projects and all the symbols in that
then yes that can get very long and in
certain functions you might find
yourself calling symbols or accessing
symbols that are in those namespaces
very often and so you might want to just
sneak in a little using namespace there
that's totally fine but specifically I
don't like using namespace STD and let's
take a look at why so first of all
looking through this code again a lot of
people would argue that yes this does
look cleaner I actually argue against
that because we may have noticed at the
beginning of this video was when I
actually had this original code here it
was incredibly easy for me to point out
what I was using from the standard
template library from C++ as library
right I didn't have to really think
twice anything that had this STD prefix
to it was from the standard library now
though if I use namespace STD well it's
a little bit difficult for me to tell
isn't it I mean you can tell just by the
naming convention fine if is not written
like a bad I mean clearly I like to
write my functions like this and kind of
Pascal case learn C++ likes this snake
case kind of format so you can still
tell via that but of course if this for
each was written like that
right in a snake case well then suddenly
it's easy to tell that it's in this file
of my example but suddenly find if is
that is that STDs fine if for each is
that the one that's in STD is there one
STD I don't know reading this code
suddenly has gotten harder for me
whereas before if I just had this for
snake case it's pretty obvious to me
that 4-h is not part of the standard
library because clearly everything that
is has that STD : : prefix and I mean
you might probably publishing it wave
this around and I mean you you might not
think that this is something that you
might run into often I mean how often I
going to write something called vector
or something called find if I mean
through writes that see out like what
kind of function name is that come on am
I really going to write that well let me
show you a real world example I work on
core technology a TA in the Frostbite
organization and we use something called
EA STL which is actually open source on
github now this is basically a
replacement for the standard template
library that comes with C++ and is
called the EA standard template library
and you can take a look at this if you
want to and since it is a bit of a
replacement the API and everything is
really meant to match what the standard
template library looks like sorry if we
take vector as an example we have this
vector dot H file and if we scroll down
you can see it is in the EA STL
namespace however the class name is the
same if we keep scrolling down here you
can see that we have class vector so
then if I'm kind of writing code at EA
how do I know if find me if I just have
vector written like that am I using EA
STL vector am i using STD vector I don't
know it's not initially very apparent to
me but it would be nice for me to see
what I'm actually using which is why if
I had that using namespace
I'd have to probably look for it
somewhere throughout my code to actually
find it and crk right i had somewhere at
the beginning of this file are using
namespace STD so i guess this is from
the STD namespace right on top of that
what if someone puts a little using
namespace EA STL somewhere well suddenly
we're getting a compiler error because
that's an ambiguous symbol the compiler
doesn't know are we referring to the STD
vector or we've are we referring to ei
STL vector on an hour man to make
matters even worse and if we kind of go
back to is just the example of having a
simple library let's just say that we
have an
space called Apple here and we have a
function called print which I don't know
let's just say it takes in a string so
Const STD string text and then we see
out this text right this seems pretty
simple to me if I scroll down over here
and make some space I'm just going to
include string up here so that this code
actually compiles and I can show you
what I mean so there we have a perfectly
reasonable function over here if I was
to call it without using namespace I
would have to call print let's actually
make this lowercase so that it looks
more like the standard library here so
if I have Apple print like that and I
don't know why it's gone made that bad
bit anyway hello there we go I'm
printing something that's pretty
reasonable let's just say that I decide
to stick a using namespace here so that
I don't have to do something like that
this suddenly becomes print hello like
this now let's say that we've introduced
another library and this is called
namespace Orange right so it's in
different libraries the orange library
and it also has a print function but
this one takes in a concert pointer
called text now let's just say that this
Orange does something a little bit
different instead of just printing this
normally what this actually does is
assigns it into a string and then
reverses the string and then prints it
so it's essentially printing out text
but in Reverse it's a bit of a malicious
function now this print here's the real
question if we use a namespace Apple and
we use namespace Orange as well then
which ones can I get cold well
previously before we actually started
using this orange library and we just
had Apple well I mean it was pretty
obvious which one gets cold it's this
one over here and if we run our program
let me just go down here and give 0 the
rest of this curd except for the same
bucket because I don't want that to run
let's hit f5 okay hello gets printed
pretty simple our function works but now
we've introduced this orange library
let's go ahead and comment that out this
seems pretty simple which one is it
gonna call now let's hit f5 oh well
you look at that it's printed out text
backwoods why is it done that well if we
look back to the code this hello is
actually a Const our array right it's
not actually a string if we don't have
this orange thing then of course what
this can actually do is something called
an implicit conversion if you guys don't
know what an implicit conversion is I've
made a video on that which is linked up
there so definitely check that out
but this performs something called an
implicit conversion because we can
convert a constraint into a string
however since we've introduced an annex
best orange library this print function
suddenly has become a better match
because this is a Const I and using this
print function we don't require any kind
of conversion doesn't have to be an
implicit conversion however there does
have to be a conversion to reach this
one so we don't get any kind of errors
on I mean zero warnings your error is
nothing like that but just by
introducing this code we've actually
started calling a different function
completely this isn't a compile error
this is a silent runtime error suddenly
all of our text is backwards that's a
nine may imagine that happening whereas
if we hadn't used namespace apple or
orange at all and we just didn't using
namespaces everywhere then our original
code would have been like that and
there's no way that that would ever
change if we just simply introduce
another library like we did with orange
it would just remain the same and
everything's great
so anyway those are my thoughts on why
using namespace can be very very bad
another really big thing that you
actually should avoid a hundred percent
of the time is using a space in a header
file never ever do that okay because who
knows where that's gonna get included
and suddenly you're using a space
somewhere where you didn't originally
intend to we have spent hours at certain
points debugging compile errors because
something declared a using namespace and
a header file and we then then got
included somewhere else it can get
really hard to track if you have any
kind of sizable project so don't ever do
it in header files if you absolutely
cannot hold yourself back from using
notice that I mean I cuz again I do do I
I do use using namespace but I usually
do it for my own kind of library stuff
right I don't do it for STD ever I don't
do it for a STL ever I actually write a
STL called column vector every single
time
never do I not do that okay because
again I want to know what I'm using and
also I want to avoid possible errors in
the future right but the biggest one is
really just looking at the code and
being able to see okay a city string
that this string class is coming from
the standard C++ library not from some
other library really easy to say really
clear but if you absolutely must use
your namespace you use it in a smaller
scope as possible if you just need it
inside an if statement use it inside an
if statement we don't just need it
inside a function which is pretty common
use it just inside that function and of
the largest scope may be a CVP file but
nanba ever do you do it in a header file
ever anyway I hope you guys enjoyed this
video let me know what your thoughts are
on using main space why do you use it
why do you not use it what's the biggest
catastrophe that's ever happened as a
result of someone using namespace when
they shouldn't have and I will see you
guys next time goodbye
[Music]